Hasyimi Bahrudin

Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia · hasyimi@gatech.edu · github.com/hasyimibhar · linkedin.com/in/hasyimi-bahrudin/

Senior backend engineer with 10 years experience, with over 3 years of experience working remotely. Interested in building distributed systems. I am also obsessed with writing readable and testable code.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Beam

Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia (Remote)

Senior Software Engineer I (Vehicles)

May 2021 - Present

- Moved to the vehicles team after reorganization. Work on backend projects related to vehicle IOT. Mostly in Go.
- Built an IOT simulator, which allows the team to test our services without requiring physical IOT
- \bullet Helped to reduce 70% of unnecessary database writes, which was causing frequent downtime due to database bloat
- Lead the microservice e2e testing project, which helped to improve developer confidence and productivity as we transition towards microservices. Most breaking changes are now caught before they get merged to master.
- Helped to write a query translator for translating Postgresql to BigQuery SQL, which is helping our transition to BigQuery as data lake

Beam

Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia (Remote)

July 2020 - May 2021

Senior Software Engineer I (Product)

- Worked as full stack engineer, writing mostly Typescript (Node.js for backend, React Native for frontend)
- \bullet Helped roll out 3DS payment in Malaysia, which improved add card success rate for Malaysia from 60% to 80%
- Optimized PostGIS queries to take advantage of geospatial indexing, which reduced latency and database CPU usage
- Implemented OpenAPI to improve API documentation and programmability, which improved developer experience

Pollen

Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia (Remote)

January 2020 - May 2020

Senior Software Engineer

- I was part of the pioneer engineers for a small pre-seed startup, writing mostly Typescript
- Helped the team to adopt Docker for local development, which improved engineer workflow
- Mentored junior engineers through PR reviews

Perlin

Singapore (Remote)

Core Engineer

August 2019 - January 2020

- I was part of the core team that was implementing the Wavelet distributed consensus protocol
- Replaced usage of LevelDB with Badger, which reduced write latency by 10x.
- Optimized memory usage when syncing state.
- Wrote a lot of tests, which increased test coverage from 40% to 70%

WhatsHalal

Singapore (Remote)

Senior Software Engineer

August 2018 - July 2019

- I was part of the pioneer engineers for a small seed-funded startup. Used mostly Go.
- Helped the company build a marketplace stack from scratch, which includes last mile delivery management
- Mentored junior engineers through PR reviews

Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia 2016 - 2018

Full Stack Developer

- I was part of a team of full stack developers. Used mostly PHP (Laravel).
- I led the project of building an in-house IOT server using Go, replacing an open-source server. This improved the overall performance of the product, and also gives us more control on how the server works.
- Helped the team to revamp their dashboard to use WebSocket instead of polling, which improved overall performance

Terato TechGames Programmer
2012 - 2015

- I was part of a small team of mobile game developers. Used mostly C++ (cocos2dx).
- Built a pseudo-3D game engine (a-la F-Zero) for a mobile badminton game. Refer to this Youtube video.
- Built a mobile game, which is a fusion of tower defense and mining (Minecraft) game. Not published.
- Built an online card collecting mobile game for the Japanese market (similar to Fantastica) with a team of 1 game producer, 2 programmers, and 3 game artists. Not published.

EDUCATION

Georgia Institute of Technology
MS Computer Science GPA: (Ongoing)

Georgia, Atlanta Fall 2019 - Spring 2023

Limkokwing University
BS Games Technology GPA: 3.8

Cyberjaya, Malaysia 2008 - 2011

SKILLS

Programming Languages: Go, Java, Python, C++, C

Areas of interest: Distributed computing, High performance computing, Compilers

OPEN SOURCE CONTRIBUTIONS

LLVM C++

reviews.llvm.org/people/commits/22060/

Casual contributor to LLVM as an effort to improve my compilers knowledge. 1 accepted patch so far.

Distributed 2D tiled engine Javascript

github.com/hasyimibhar/voffice-crdt

Proof of concept for a distributed 2D tiled engine (virtual office) built on top of CRDT (yjs).